Guide to the Leigh N. Ortenburger Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 9: American Alpine Club
  - AAC annual meetings, 1986, 1988, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - AAC Membership Committee, correspondence, 1974, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - AAC Guide Certification Committee, correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - AAC Access Fund, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - AAC Teton Ranch Committee, correspondence, 1970-1990 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Equipment, rope tests, no date (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - AAC Equipment Committee, correspondence, notes, 1956-1960 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - AAC Equipment Committee, responses to questionnaires on packs, transceivers, tents, sleeping bags, stoves (Box 32, Folder 1-7)
  - AAC Equipment Committee, army specifications, 1949-1953 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - AAC Expeditions Committee, correspondence, 1955-1962 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - AAC Expeditions Committee, applications, 1965-1975 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - AAC Expeditions Committee, correspondence, 1970-1991 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - AAC Expeditions Committee, applications, 1985-1990 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - AAC Expeditions Committee, applications, 1991-1995 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
- Series 10: Expeditions
  Ortenburger, Leigh N., went on ten mountaineering expeditions to the Cordillera Blanca in Peru, one to Aconcagua in Argentina, and one to Makalu in Nepal that was led by Sir Edmund Hillary. This series contains newspaper articles, magazine articles, maps, and notes about mountaineering in Peru, specific information about Leigh Ortenburger's expeditions, and correspondence, including: Abell, Jane; Abrons, Henry L.; Ames, Alcides; Allmon, Charles; Amatt, John R.; Angeles, Eugenio; Angeles, Macario; Anglada, Jose Manuel; Atherton, David; Ayres, Fred D.; Barcham, H. P.; Beckey, Fred; Bell, George I.; Benavides, Victor; Berlin, Nathaniel I.; Bingham, Alfred M.; Bishop, Barry; Bolinder, Anders; Bonington, Christian; Buckingham, William J. (Bill); Calegari, Nino; Carter, H. Adams; Clark, Ronald W.; Connor, Ed; Cook, Oscar A.; Corbet, Barry; Cox, Brian; Crausaz, Winston; Creswell, Alexander E.; Crow, Pieter; Davis, David S.; De Gasperi, Vincenzo; Del Fium, Dorene; Dienhart, John W.; Dingman, David L.; Doig, Liz; Doody, Carrie G.; Doody, Daniel E.; Dornan, David; Dunn, Sharon K.; Dyhrenfurth, G. O.; Ebert, John; Echevarria, Evelio; Edwards, Dalton W.; Everett, Jr., Boyd N.; Farquhar, Francis P.; Freixas Fuentes, Joan; Fritz, Dietrich; Frost, Thomas M.; Ganci, Joseph David (Dave); Gill, Michael; Glidden, Jocelyn C. (Jock); Gocking, Roger; Goody, Richard; Grajales, Fernando; Greul, Hans Dieter; Gtiobbi, Domingo; Gurtner, Othman; Hamano, Yoshio; Harrah, David,; Harrison, John C.; Hauser, Gunter; Healey, David; Henderson, Kenneth A.; Henostroza Lliuya, Fidencio; Hiebeler, Toni; Hillary, Sir Edmund; Hoerlin, Herman W.; Hoessly, Peter; Hofmann, Walther; Horn, Rick; Hoyt, Fletcher; Huber, Hermann; Hultgren, Herbert N.; Humphreys, John S.; Irvin, Richard K; Jamanca Lliuya, Lucio; Janis, Burt; Kadison, Alexander; Kauffman, Andrew J.; Kendall, Henry W.; Kendall, John P.; Kennedy, Michael; Kinzl, Hans; Klier, Heinrich; Kneebone, Terry; Koch, Alfred; Kosmath, Ernst F.; Lahiri, S.; Lahr, Bill; Lawrence, John H.; Liska, Donald; Lofthouse, Richard W.; Lopez de Castro, Jose; Lottinville, Savoie; Lowe, George; Lowe, W. George; Lukis, Karen; Manning, Dan; Mardon, D. K.; Marmillod, Dorly; Marmillod, Frederic; Martel Davila, Teofanes; Matthews, W. V. Graham; McAllister, Otis; McKibben, M. Craig; McWherter, Michael; Menostruza Lliuya, Fidencio; Merrihue, Craig M.; Michael, David; Milledge. James S.; Millikan, Rick; Mohling, Franz; Morales Arnao, Cesar; Mulgrew, Peter D.; Muller, H. R.; Mutch, Thomas A. (Tim); Naas, Charles W.; Nakagawa, Magoichi; Nakamura, Tomatsu; Nevison, Thomas O.; Oberlin, John C.; Ortenburger, Irene B.; Ortenburger, Leigh N.; Paragot, Robert; Patterson, Leif-Norman; Peck, Annie; Perce, Robert; Perkins, Marlin; Pugh, L. Griffith C.; Read, William A. (Al); Reese, Rick; Ricker, John; Robbins, Royal; Romanes, Walter; Ross, Kermith F.; Ruefl, E. G.; Sabat, F.; Schatz, Ruedi; Schmid, Rudi; Schneider, Erwin; Schoon, Andre; Schreve, Frank H.; Seki, Tsuneyoshi; Siri, William E.; Smech, Karl Werner; Smith, Bill; Steck, Allen; Summers, Martin; Swan, Lawrence W.; Taugwalder, Rudolf; Thorington, J. Monroe; Trabado de la Fuente, Antonio; Vargas Angeles, Eliseo; Velaochaga, Carlos; Wallace, William; Walton, Harold F.; Warburton, Mike; Ward, Michael P.; Wells, Matthew; Welsch, Walter; West, John B.; Whillans, Don; Whitmore, George; Wilburn, Jr., Harold S.; Williamson, Jed; Wilson, Kenneth J.; Wilson, Ted; Yokochi, Yasuo; Yoshizawa, Ichiro, et al. There is a section on general correspondence in 33.14 and 34.1-34.2, the expeditions are arranged by year and also contain correspondence, and folder 36.11 contains a list of the expeditions, with personnel, peaks climbed, and publications.
  - Peru, articles on mountaineering (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Peru, miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
  - Arhuaco Indians of Colombia, typescript, author unknown (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Peru, Hitotsubashi University Andes Expedition, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Peru, Waseda Andes Expedition, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Peru, mountaineering bibliography (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Crow, Pieter, correspondence re Marmillod, Frederic and Dorly, 1981-1984 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Crausaz, Winston, correspondence re Pico de Orizaba in Mexico, 1981, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Ricker, John, correspondence re guidebook "Yurac Janka," 1965-1982 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Goody, Richard, "Tayapampa in the Alpamayo Valley," correspondence 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Peru, miscellaneous correspondence, A-H, 1966-1990 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Peru, miscellaneous correspondence, J-O, 1954-1990 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Peru, miscellaneous correspondence, P-Z and unknown (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Peru, clippings, Peruvian Times, 1950s-1980s (Box 34, Folder 3-6)
  - Peru, clippings, date unknown (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Peck, Annie, clippings (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Peck, Annie, notes and correspondence (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Peck, Annie, articles re climb of North Peak of Huascarán (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Peru, correspondence with Saturday Evening Post, 1958-1959 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Peru, correspondence with National Geographic, 1954-1962 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - University of California High Altitude Expedition, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - American Andean Expedition, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Proposed expedition to K2, correspondence, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Proposed expedition to K2, logistics planning (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - North American Andean Expedition, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - North American Andean Expedition, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Makalu Expedition, Hillary, Sir Edmund, correspondence, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Makalu Expedition, clippings (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Himalayan/Karakoram miscellaneous clippings (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Makalu Expedition, American Alpine Journal article reprint, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Makalu articles, reprints (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., letters from Makalu, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Hillary, Edmund, and Doig, Desmond, dispatches from Makalu to Opera Mundi (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Nepal bibliography on cards (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - North American Andean Expedition, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 12-13)
  - North American Andean Expedition, correspondence re death of Doody, Daniel (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - North American Andean Expedition, correspondence, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Perutah Expedition, correspondence, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Perutah Expedition, summary and manuscripts, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Perutah Expedition, miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - American Andean Expedition, correspondence, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - American Andean Expedition, maps, manuscripts, article, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - American Andean Expedition, miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Peru Expedition, correspondence and maps, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 8-10)
  - Peru Expeditions, 1982, and 1985, and Aconcagua, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh N., chronology, lists of expeditions with publications, peaks, and personnel (Box 36, Folder 12)
- Series 11: Maps
  - Map indices, Western United States, Western Canada (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Wyoming maps (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Himalayan maps (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Unsorted photos and maps (Box 37, Folder 4)
- Series 12: Typescripts by Other Authors
  This series contains typescripts by other authors.
  - Harlin, John, typescript on Eiger climb (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Harlin, John, typescript on Teton mountaineering (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - McWherter, Michael, draft typescript re Ortenburger, Leigh N., for Summit Magazine, unpublished (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Cohen, Michael P., "How Does One Defend a Brittle Thesis?" (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Corbet, Barry, essays (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Green, Peter G., typescripts re Peru, Denali38.7 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Cronin, Bill, syllabus to "The American West Since 1850" (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Reese, Rick, "Speed Record on Grand Teton in 1939," "Little Cottonwood Canyon," typescripts (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Sinclair, Pete, proposal for "The Last Innocent Americans" (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Sinclair Pete, "The Last Innocent Americans," typescript (Box 38, Folder 11-12)
  - Sinclair, Pete, more typescripts, 1966, 1987-1988 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Sinclair, Pete, roast for Irvine, Robert (Bob) on his 20th year in the National Park Service (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Turiano, Thomas, "New Routes, New Challenges: Tetons," typescript (Box 38, Folder 15)
- Series 13: Correspondence, Incoming and Outgoing, 13
  This series contains incoming correspondence, 1952-1991, filed alphabetically, from the following: Ablondi, Robert T.; Althouse, Ivan G.; Amatt, John R.; Ayres, Fred D.; Bachman, Kirk; Baumgartner, Ernestine L.; Beardsley, Grace; Beardsley, George; Belcher, C. Francis; Bell, George I.; Bennett, Ross S.; Blaurock, Carl; Bolyard, Dudley W.; Bonney, Lorraine G.; Borneman, Walter R.; Bradley, Peter A.; Buckingham, William J; Bull, Robert; Burnette, Floyd; Butler, Marjorie; Byrd, Jo Anne; Campbell, Thomas; Carson, Bruce; Carter, H. Adams; Caughron, R. D.; Clark, Ed; Clark-Snider, Jennifer; Clinch, Nicholas; Clyde, Norman; Conrod, William; Cornell, Alice M.; Coulter, Henry W.; Crenshaw, Jane; Durrance, John R. (Jack); Dallett, F. J.; Davidson, Leigh; Davidson, Les; D'Evelyn, Linda; Dingman, David L.; Donaghey, Lee; Dornan, David; Dorward, James; Dorkman, Oskar; Duerr, Steve; Dyhrenfurth, Norman G.; Eastman, Barb; Ehrman, Eleanor; Eltzroth, Richard; Enoch, Jennifer; Farquhar, Margery; Fascell, Dante B.; Favinger, John; Farabee, Butch; Frost, Thomas M.; Fryxell, Jenny; Fryxell, Penelope; Gagner, Paul; Ganci, Joseph David (Dave); Gardiner, Steve; Glidden, Jocelyn C. (Jock); Gocking, Roger; Gran, Art; Green, Peter G.; Greenwood, Sallie; Harrington, Randall P.; Hart, Stephen H.; Hechtel, Lisa; Hechtel, Richard; Hemming, Gary; Hemming, John; Henke, Rich; Hilbert, H. S.; Hirsch, Karen; Hoeman, J. Vin; Horn, John J.; Hornbein, Thomas F.; Horwood, Ruby; Houston, Elinor; Houston, Bruce; Huidekoper, Jim; Hultgren, Herbert N.; Irvin, Richard K.; Irvine, Robert and Marie; Jackson, Reynold G.; Jacquot, Raymond G.; Jones, Glenn; Jones, Chris; Karplus, Curtis M.; Kauffman, Andrew J.; Kaufman, William C.; Kendall, Henry W.; Kimbrough, Thomas; Knauth, Felix; Kramer, Tony; Kriebel, Robert; Langer, George; LeBon, Leo; Lemon, John C.; Lerum, Annie; Lipman, Peter; Liu, Rick; Lewis, Bill; Love, J. David; Lowe, George; Luck, Shirley Crisman; Madsen, Lynn; Matous, Ron; Matthews, W. V. Graham; McCrary, Kay; McDougal, Paula J.; McDonald, Patty; Melton, Mark; Merriam, Robert W.; Milligan, Sharlene; Mitchell, George J.; Molenaar, Dee; Montopoli, George; Moore, Alexandra; Mullen, Frances A.; Nash, Roderick; Nelson, Doyle; Neptune, Gary; O'Brien, John; Olson, James; Ortenburger, Ann; Ortenburger, Arthur, Jr.; Ortenburger; Carolyn D.; Ortenburger, Robert D.; Ortenbuurger, Teresa A.; Ortenburger, Thomas; Owen, Harry; Perch, Rich; Pownall, Richard; Read, William A. (Al); Reese, Rick; Regan, Elizabeth A.; Reschenberg, Dale; Reschenberg, Leslie (Haning); Resor, Bill; Riddell Lee; Riddel, Ed; Righter, Robert W.; Roach, Deirdre; Roach, Gerry; Robbins, Royal; Roper, Steve; Rosebrough, Robert F.; Salvador, Nick; Saxon, Bill D.; Schatz, Ruedi; Schmid, Rudi; Shepherd, Phil; Sinclair, Pete; Siri, William E.; Smith, Sara; Smutek, Ray; Snyder, Jennifer; Stafford, Bruce; Steck, Allen; Stephenson, Jack; Stettner, Paul; Sutton, John; Susong, Kelly Milligan; Talbot, Lee M.; Terray, Lionel; Tingey, Ralph; Turiano, Thomas; Turnbull, Gwynn; Turner, Thomas A.; Tutwiler, Margaret de B.; Unsoeld, Willi; Unsoeld, Jolene; Valsing, Ruth Hubbard; Villard, Jr., O. G.; Vlahakis, Alisa; Vogel, Beatrice; Wurdock, Willi; Wallace, William; Warburton, Mike; Waldie, Scott; Waterman, Jonathan; West, Judy; Wexler, Arnold; Wheelock, Walter; White, Elizabeth; White, Gene; Williamson, Jed; Whitesel, John A.; Wilson, Ted; Woodward, Stanley; Woolsey, Elizabeth D.; Wurdegar, David. In addition there is outgoing correspondence saved from Leigh Ortenburger's computer at the time of his death, 1983-1991, filed by date. Folder 40.7 contains alphabetical and date indexes to these letters to the following: Ablondi, Robert T.; Adams, Willard N.; Alderman Library; Althouse, Ivan G.; Anderson, Owen; Armington, Peter; Avenali, Peter Cado; Ayres, Irene; Ayres, Angela (Mrs. Fred D.; Baldwin, Ralph; Barmore, William J.; Beardsley, George; Beardsley, Grace; Beardsley, Irene; Bearss, Ed; Beckey, Fred; Behrens, John; Beiser, Mike; Bell, Alan; Bell, George I.; Bennett, Ross S.; Bennett, Tom; Berman, Rick; Beyer, Jim; Bjornstadt, Eric; Black, Donnie; Black, Rick; Boaden, Ann; Borneman, Walter R.; Bossier, Tex; Bowman, Eddie; Boynton, Beverley; Bradley, Peter A.; Bradley, Peter A. and Eileen; Brady, Jim; Brafford, C. J.; Breitenberger, Eric; Bricher-Wade, Sheila; Brooks, Gordon; Buchwald, Caryl E.; Buckingham, Edna; Buckingham, William J. (Bill); Burns, John; Butler, Marjorie; Carson, Andy; Carter, H. Adams; Cattabriga, Keith; Chessler, Mike; Chouinard, Yvon; Clinch, Nicholas; Clinton, Jack; Coelho, Mary; Cornell, Alice M.; Coulter, Henry W.; Craighead, Margaret Smith; Crausaz, Winston; Deak, Jon; Deep Springs Class of 1948; Deukmejian, George; Diem, Kenneth L.; Dingman, David L.; Dodds, Gordon B.; Donini, Jim; Dornan, David; Downer, Gene; Duerr, Steve; DuMais, Richard; Durrance, John R. (Jack); Dykes, Jeff; Eastman, Barb; Ebert, S. John; Echevarria, Evelio; Eichorn, Jules M.; Elder, Kelly; Engberg, Eric; EPA Wood Heater Program; Farabee, Butch; Farquhar, Margery; Farquhar, Peter; Feiges, William; Field, Charles; Fink, Robert; Firestone, Caroline; Fitch, Chuck; Fletcher, Ms.; Fowler, Charlie; Fox, Alisa (Vlahakis); Freedley, John; Freedom of Information Act Appeals Officers; Friedman, Howard; Frost, Thomas M.; Fryxell, Fritiof M.; Fryxell, Jenny; Gagner, Paul; Ganci, Joseph David (Dave); Garber, Ren; Gardiner, Steve; Garland, R. Scott; Glidden, Jocelyn C. (Jock); Gocking, Roger; Goldstone, Richard J.; Gowans, Frederick R.; Graham, Robert; Gray, W. H., III; Green, Peter G.; Greenwood, Sallie; Gressley, Gene M.; Grissom, Kitty Calhoun; GTE Government Systems; Guthrie, John D.; Haines, Aubrey; Haning, Leslie; Harkness, John; Harrington, Randal P.; Harrington, Susie; Harvard Mountaineering Club; Hawken, Ken; Hechtel, Richard; Henke, Rich; Hollis, Joan; Hollis, Peter; Hong, Rex; Horn, Rick; Horton, Paul; Huber, Jennie; Indefatigable Whomsoever; Irvin, Richard K.; Irvine, Marie; Irvine, Robert; Jackson Hole Guide; Jackson Hole News; Jackson, Reynold G.; Jacquot, Raymond G.; Jamanca Lliuya, Lucio; Jern, Ken; Jervis, Steven; Jonas, Mark T.; Karplus, Curtis M.; Kehoe, Mike; Keith, Jason; Kimbrough, Robert; Kimbrough, Tom; King, Jon; Koch, Dave; Koedt, Peter; Kostmayer, Peter; Krause, William L.; Kriebel, Robert; Krisjansons, Juris; Lamb, George R.; Lang, William; Larson, Leo; Larson, Norm; Larwood, III, Mark; Layton, Trish; LeCooksware; Lemon, John C.; Lemon, Kay; Lerch, Nicki; Lerum, Annie; Lev, Peter; Love, J. David; Love, Jane; Lowe, Alex; Lowe, George; Lowe, Jeff; Lugbill, Kent; Maloney, Jennifer R.; Manifor, Richard; Manns, Tim; Martel Davila, Teofanes; Marvel, Christopher C.; Massey, Rheba; Matous, Ron; Mattes, Merrill; Matthews, Mary Ann; McCain, Jr., Art; McCarthy, James P.; McWherter, Michael; Medrick, Rick; Menocal, Armando; Merriam, Robert W.; Merrill, Marly; Merrill, Prof.; Merrill, Mrs.; Merry Christmas; Mintzmyer, Lorraine; Mish, Stan; Montopoli, George; Moore, Alexandra (Harvard Mt. Club); Morales Arnao, Cesar; Morgan, Becky; Morrissey, James D.; Mountain Gear; Mowat, John; Munger, Mike; Myhre, Paul; Nash, Roderick; Nelson, Doyle; Neptune Mountaineering; Nissley, Claudia; North American Wildlife Foundation; Northrup, Jim; Olson, Curtis; Olson, Jim; Ortenburger, Betty; Ortenburger, Carolyn D.; Ortenburger, Arthur I., Jr.; Ortenburger, Robert D.; Ortenburger, Teresa A.; Parker, Doug; Pell, Claiborne; Peninsula Booksearch; Perch, Rich; Pistono, John; Platts, Doris; Pollack, Cathy; Porzak, Glenn; Powers, Dan; Quinlan, Stephen; Rafferty, Neil; Raynolds, John and William; Recreational Equipment, Inc.; Reed, John C., Jr.; Reese, Rick; Reese, Marylee; Reese, Rick; Reschenberg, Leslie (Haning); Resor, Bill; Richter, Bob and Sherry; Ridenour, James; Righter, Robert W.; Righter, Sherry; Roach, Gerry; Rockefeller, Laurance S.; Rogers, Jerry L.; Roscoe, Jim; Rosebro, Bob; Rubin, Alan; Rudd, Robert; Satterfield, Chuck; Schenk, Jeb; Schmotzer, Connie; Schultz, Robert P.; Secor, R. J.; Sher, Byron; Silva, Robert S.; Sinclair, Connie; Sinclair, Pete; Siri, William E.; Snyder, J. C.; Spitler, John; Spritz, Richard A.; Stark, Jack E.; Stark, Jack E.; State of California; Steck, Allen; Stettner, Joe; Stettner, Paul; Stewart, Sandy; Storjohann, Don; Stoughton, Herbert W.; Stroock, Betty; Sylvester, Arthur G.; Talbot, Lee M.; Talbot, Martha H.; Tankersley, Tom; Taylor, Rob; Thatcher, Bryce; Thomas, William H.; Thompson, Gray; Thompson, Jerry; Thuermer, Angus M.; Timberpeg Pacific; Tompkins, Hal; Toombes, Guy; Toshiba America; Troy, Rich; Trull, William; Tuckey, John; Turiano, Thomas; Turnbull, Gwynn; Unsoeld, Jolene; Utica Public Library; Vaill, Ted; Vlahakis, Alisa; Wade, Ian; Walcott, William, Mrs.; Walker, Steven; Wallop, Malcolm; Walter, Jackson; Walton, Harold F.; Warvurton, Ann; Warburton, Mike; Warner, Melissa; Warren, Tom; Watkin, Tony; Watson, Rick; Weber, Ron; Whitesel, John A.; Whiton, Mark; Whittlesey, Lee H.; Wiese, Lynn; Wilcox, Rick; Wilson, Sherman; Wilson, Ted; Wilts, Chuck; Witesman, Fred; Woodmencey, James; Woods, Don and Montgomery, John; Woolsey, Elizabeth D.; Wright, Margaret; Wunsch, Steve; Yager, Mike; Yokell, Mike, et al.
  - Incoming correspondence A-O, through 1991 (Box 39, Folder 1-10)
  - Incoming correspondence P-Z, through 1991 (Box 40, Folder 1-4)
  - Incoming correspondence, unidentified (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing correspondence, to Palo Alto Unified School District, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing correspondence, index to files on Ortenburger, Leigh N.'s computer, 1987-1991 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 40, Folder 8-12)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 41, Folder 1-27)
- Series 14: Original writing, by Ortenburger, Leigh N.
  This series contains original writing by Ortenburger, Leigh N. It includes college applications, papers written at Deep Springs College, the first and last editions of A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range, several other small publications, two obituaries, and articles in the American Alpine Journal and the Sierra Club Bulletin about his expeditions.
  - Reprints and copies of articles in the American Alpine Journal (AAJ) (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Deep Springs College (DSC) application, partial draft (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Rhodes Scholarship application, part F (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Papers on political philosophy, under Dr. G. H. Sabine, DSC (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Introductory Economics exam, DSC (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Essay on Reichenbach's Calculus of Propositions, DSC (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Essay on Foundations of Mathematics, DSC (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Non-Euclidean Geometry, typescript, DSC (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Typescripts of new Teton climbs for AAJ, 1956-1970, 1981, 1897 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - National Climbing Classification Proposal, Summit Magazine, May 1963 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Obituaries for Buckingham, William J., AAJ 1991, and Harlin, John (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - The Last Unclimbed Peak, draft and final version about climb of minor peak in Leigh Canyon with Kimbrough, Thomas, photo of Mt. Kimburger (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous typescripts (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Notes for slide show on Peru for Harvard Mountaineering Club, 4/20/1989 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Reviews of writing by Ortenburger, Leigh N. (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - "Complete List of Teton Routes," 5/27/1990 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - "A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range," first edition, 1956, "Ascents of the Grand Teton, 1898-1974," "The Grand Teton, 1984" (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - "A Climber's Guide to the Teton Range," revised edition, 1965, Leigh N. Ortenburger and Reynold G. Jackson, "A Complete Guide to the Teton Range," third edition, 1996, and a list of the editions (Box 42, Folder 18)
- Series 15: Photography
  This series contains all the photographs by Ortenburger, Leigh N., remaining in the collection, starting with mounted and unmounted photos, mostly black and white. He specialized in large-format photos of mountain scenes in Peru, the Tetons, Nepal, various other mountain localities, and some archeological ruins. The size given for mounted prints is the outer mount size; the size for the unmounted prints is the actual photo size. (There are some aerial photos taken by Austin Post in the 1960s.) There is an extensive set of 8x10" unmounted prints from the Peru expeditions, some of which are dated and/or identified on the back. This is followed by a complete set of negatives and color transparencies, in his filing order, which was chronological with respect to years, but unordered within each year. With the exception of 1952 and 1954 he did not number or identify his negatives systematically. Negatives have been filed with contact prints, if available, and a card reflecting the details of the printing process regarding dodging and burning for the better enlargements. Identification attempts by the collection processor are contained in brackets. Much more work could be done with the collection to connect 8x10"s with negatives, years, and subjects.
  - Subseries 15.1: Early photos, some mounted, taken with 2¼" x 3¼" camera, starting in 1949, including the Tetons, Sierras, and Colorado
    - Early photos, some mounted, taken with 2¼" x 3¼" camera, starting in 1949, including the Tetons, Sierras, and Colorado (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 15.2: Early photos of Tetons, all mounted, mounted size 10x13"
    - Tetons from String Lake Bridge, Hangover Pinnacle, Teewinot, possibly Symmetry Spire with Templeton's Crack (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Grand Teton from Idaho, Guided Party with Exum, Glenn, Teton Range from Jackson Lake (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Teewinot from Jenny Lake, Mount Owen from Amphitheatre, Drizzlepuss and East Horn of Mount Moran, the Grand Teton and Teewinot (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Possibly Dike Pinnacle on Middle Teton, the range, Mount Moran, North Face of Grand Teton (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - North Face of Grand Teton with climber (unidentified), climber leading (unidentified), Grand Teton and Mount Owen (Box 54, Folder 5)